[Music]
tv 18 present india risk management
award honoring the new age risk
management practitioners the word risk
has assumed a whole new meaning in the
last three years first because of the
pandemic and more recently because of
the totally unexpected russia ukraine
war but one organization and its leader
icsa lombard and its managed return ceo
bhargav dasgupta have been kind of
goading india inc towards the
understanding of risk management for the
last eight years they have been
supporting cnbc 318's initiative for an
india risk management awards and this
year there were 550 companies that were
putting their hands up to participate in
these awards well today i have the man
himself uh bhagavddasgupta to speak to
us about insights into risk management
and how the current context for risk has
changed visited thank you very much
indeed for joining me today thank you
for having me
pleasure well let me start with what is
confronting us right now the russia
ukraine war it's quite possible that the
geopolitical kaleidoscope will change
rather dramatically and
maybe yesterday's allies will be
tomorrow on opposite sides and
yesterday's enemies will be tomorrow's
allies now in such an environment
how do companies prepare for sudden
drops and sudden stops in supply chains
and commodities
these are what we call the six sigma
events right black spot events that
you can't really predict and prepare for
what you can do is have an organization
that is
as agile as flexible as resilient as
possible
but it's easier than that now if you
look at just this one particular
incident uh you know it's very difficult
to predict the future is a very
hazardous game but as you rightly said
it's it's highly possible that this will
potentially change the world order
um we've had you know
since the cold war you know broke down
you know ended in 1991 we've had a
certain world order yeah we've benefited
from the world already done the
globalization because you know
countries have worked with each other
we've seen trade we've seen commerce
and and all of that potential is
threatened
uh so one of the things that we do worry
about is what you just said that you
know we could end into
a kind of a bipolar world or a multiple
world
and
that itself would have a tremendous
impact in terms of the uh global uh
geopolitics and global uh in
globalization and and economic impact
for uh different organizations
uh even assuming this war comes to an
end which is to me it looks like a
optimistic scenario given what we're
just seeing in terms of the bhushan
killings etc and the global outrage
but even let's say our best case
scenario the world comes to an end i
think the impact of the sanctions will
stay for some more time so the other
impact that we will see is higher
community prices
um uh interest rate going up inflation
going up and that has consequences
and the last thing that i'll talk about
is what we've been calling you know
people have been calling methodization
of finance and trade
and what it does in terms of the global
order that you talked about is to be
seen
uh as i said i think all what
organizations can do is be very
resilient very close to the ground and
uh
and be nimble in terms of what you know
how they adjust to it uh but it's uh you
know more
it's easier said than done
from india's perspective i think there
is an opportunity because uh
today you know in the pandemic time we
talked about china plus one strategy i
think there is clearly an opportunity
for india to
increase trade and commerce and increase
our markets manufacturing base
because of exactly the reasons that we
talked about uh global narrative is
shifted to uh you know dividing the
world into free
countries and countries which are not so
free and india clearly potentially falls
into the first camp and there is
possibility that more of the outsourcing
would go into countries like india
which has a base the capability the
manpower to support the world in terms
of locality
you know during corvid i'm sure you had
to part with a lot of the information to
your agents and sales agents which you
would have otherwise kept very
close to you in your close servers
i heard this even more from bankers
because of apps you know a lot of data
had to be given up which they would
originally house only within their own
devices now do you see therefore cyber
risk as another very big possible six
sigma or a near a six sigma event
uh absolutely and look at the end of the
day as organizations uh you know given
what happened during covet the lockdowns
all of us had to
uh rapidly transform and increase our
digitization levels right you know some
of us are doing it but
at scale most organizations have to do
this without that without in future
there is no survival so you have to
delete it there's no choice
just because of the concern of rights
you cannot say that i will be isolated
from the destruction
and now as you do that uh clearly there
is increased risk uh you know we've seen
the impact of the work from home also
increasing this risk in this period uh
it's just because the last year over the
previous year right the number of cyber
attacks have had a 400 increase
some of the surveys that you know others
have done what we understand is that
roughly 60 percent of corporates have
suffered some kind of transparency
and when you when an attack of that
nature happens there are losses both to
yourself uh what in insurance we call
first party losses so the cost of a
ransomware payment if you have to take
one the foreign six and the recovery you
know cost the business interruption the
reputation loss so these are losses to
yourself but there's also the third
party laws that you're referring to
which is loss of customer data and
potentially a liability suit against you
because of that
now
you know there is no clear easy answer
to solve for this as an organization you
have to stay as vigilant and as prepared
uh you know in terms of having your
cyber security and cyber risk management
policy having your governance framework
your operational team dedicated team
which understands this and monitors this
risk
what we call you know threat hunting and
certain intelligence and a crisis
handling protocols if something goes
wrong on a certain day
but in spite of all of this there is a
high possibility that something will
will break something
[Music]
laid down so that you know how to react
to it uh as fast as possible as an
organization
and beyond all of that as we keep saying
you know finally you should take cyber
insurance because that's the only way to
protect yourself from some of these
problems not everything but this is in
my opinion a way of life this is
something that we as organizations have
to be prepared for and the real worry
that we would have really is that this
is becoming the way of uh you know
fighting wars across countries
absolutely and your nation states you
know playing some of these uh roles uh
you know the the the bad actors as we
call it uh in this space and that's
something that we
as a nation we need to prepare for oh
absolutely i mean
let me add that question then you know
as a risk management tool do you think
as a nation or at least the financial
sector say people like reserve bank
sebby erda
or even large organizations like
yourself
need to have a movement almost or a
mission mode of consumer education
because after all often the data breach
or the giveaway of precious data comes
from the consumer isn't it you give away
your aadhaar card or you give away some
crucial number
yeah you know more than ever you know
it's just the
card
is absolutely valid uh i think
systematically particularly the
financial services industry we probably
need to do a lot more in terms of
creating customer awareness i've seen
reserve bank do a lot uh you know we see
those ads paying but i think
collectively as institutions as
out your money from organization account
has been swept up
in the insurance sector we have not seen
the consumer impact as of now uh you
know but what we've done is we've
launched products for retail customers
where
even at an individual level you can buy
policies and protect yourself from some
of these costs and losses uh up to a cap
uh
that's something people will get
get popular but i agree with you that
doesn't as a as a collective uh you know
the regulators institutions
uh you know and companies we need to do
a lot more in terms of creating events
and also i i strongly believe and i'm
sure there is a lot of work going on in
terms of at a national level
uh we need
you know national protection against the
cyber risk that we are facing
as an organization and especially a
leader in the insurance space
how does icic lombard help corporates
manage their risk traditionally the role
uh you know you started the session by
talking about what we've been trying to
do in the last eight years creating
awareness so around that time we felt
that as an insurance player
uh the role that we've kind of
crafted for ourselves is very very
limited just talking about the fact that
if there's a claim i mean you give us a
premium if there's a ppp
that's of course our key role but can we
expand our role to say that
can we work with corporates to mitigate
the risk and reduce the probability of a
claim in the first place and we have you
know a lot of data we have experienced
we have
uh comparison able to compare benchmark
uh
there are a lot of technology tools that
are resolving and you know we felt that
we were you know time was right for us
to do that so the approach that we've
taken over these years is to
use some of these capabilities data
analytics you know uh experience uh
capability technology to provide exactly
that uh your service to customers not
just risk transfer as insurance but also
risk management and mitigation so i'll
give you a small a few examples so uh
today we have uh you know sensors
tracking some of our you know customers
carbons to help them prevent hijacking
losses or for refrigerated cargos
preventing losses because of temperature
fluctuations we've had sensors in some
of the premises of our operands where
there may be a fire safety system but we
don't know whether the water pressure is
you know stable and adequate toward the
point again with the sensor you can we
can
give more you know messages or you know
wanting messages to customers whenever
it goes below a threshold so just to
give you a couple of examples
but this is the journey that we believe
insurance sector needs to take in terms
of moving towards playing a bigger role
in terms of risk management solutions
and while i give some technology based
uh examples there's a lot that we can do
in terms of helping customers with
advisory work in the benchmarking in
terms of uh you know what we call asset
valuation
drone based surveys thermography lots of
stuff that we've been doing which can be
done at scale which helps customers our
corporates reduce their exposure or
reduce their risk
actually your uh sector has been
foremost in using machine learning and
artificial intelligence
i hear of insurers saying that
very often because we are able to feed
the computers with accident data
often you don't really need a third
party to even visit or even your own
staff to visit say a car accident site
or
the victim
because
the machine is able to provide most of
it from the pictures provided by the
customer you know you have taken ai and
machine learning to new highs is does it
come handy even in your risk management
advice to companies or customers
we are experimenting so one of the
things that we could do during this
period particularly the cohort lockdown
so we do a risk inspection before we
give a cover to a new client right
if it's corporate
now we could do that through virtual
risk inspections uh we had that
capability for our motor survey we use
the same capability for uh you know our
corporate customers in this period what
we are now doing is scaling some of
those up again virtually you don't have
to have people you know traveling to the
factories but you know virtually we are
able to
survey your site we may be you may be in
you know some corner of the country you
know and
the access may be uh you know may not be
great but you're able to do that
what you can also add to it and you know
there are solutions that are evolving we
can add augmented reality on on top of
it and allow
the risk engineers to give better
quality decision because they are also
getting you know inputs from other
experienced
sources where we just kind of convert
into digitized knowledge
and that's helping them in terms of
you know
providing better and better advice
lastly small volume claims you know we
talked about motor insurance but small
value and corporate claims you kind of
uh now as a company we've launched a
capability on with launch service a user
using ai you know
your ai and ml solution where small
volume uh small value corporate claims
are also getting paid without any
uh physical intervention completely
digitized using aim so yes there's a lot
of scope to use some of these
capabilities to scale up operations and
actually make it more convenient and
faster for customers to benefit from
that fair point well i have more
questions for you on what are the key
lessons that management and insurers
have picked up posts covered it's a big
event in our lives those questions to mr
dhaas gupta after the break
[Music]
care lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management award honoring the
new age risk management practitioners
[Music]
ici 10 bombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management award honoring the
new age risk management practitioner
welcome back to this special chat with
mr bhagava the manager and ceo of icici
lombard we have been discussing his
insights into risk management
uh mrs dascuk thank you for your
patience well uh you know post covered a
lot of companies are now getting back to
pre-covering what you can call normalcy
mode now
what should change how should they
prepare for risk
you know
my personal view is that the two biggest
lessons that we've learned from the
pandemic are uh one the importance of
resilience and the second is the
importance of empathy
first for your business and second for
your employees
uh and uh
and my senses a lot of organizations
have learned that lesson at least for
the immediate future
you guys think stabilize and if you
don't have any more prices people forget
these lessons but as at this point in
time those are lessons that have been
learned
and you know traditionally in the past
as an organization we've been trying to
optimize everything right you know cut
down costs manage inventory and you know
just in time inventory don't build
redundancies you just focus on
efficiency i think you've learned the
lesson that resilience is important
uh that's one the second one which is on
the on the employee side i think the
importance of empathy is very very
important to all of us what we're seeing
is organizations are also
you know responding to this i mean
actually factoring this in terms of
let's say the
employee practices the policies that
they have they're clearly a lot more you
know employee-centric
we are seeing a recognition of mental
health you know which
really most organizations didn't bother
about even in our health policies people
are seeking some of those
uh you know services mental health
counseling for example
we are seeing a lot of virtualization of
healthcare consumption so uh you know in
the past when corporates would take
health policies
they would only pay for hospitalization
today a lot of them are seeking out
services which are beyond
hospitalization okay telling health
so there's a tremendous change in terms
of the type of services that they
they're seeking driven by those two
points that i made empathy towards your
employees and uh a lot more focus on
resilience of operations beyond just
optimization well that's fascinating
this adaptation uh by indian corporates
uh well actually if we had not gone
through kovid i think my discussion
would have concentrated more on climate
change which is you know another big
event outside our lives but impinging on
all corporate and individual decisions
now
you know disaster risk management or uh
you know it's always considered it's not
considered part of mainstream climate
change preparation do you think that is
changing now and disastrous management
is getting embedded into broadly
preparing for climate change what are
your views on this so if you look at the
number of
catastrophic losses that we've had
because of weather related reasons
last year we had about 329 billion
dollars of
catastrophic losses which are weather
related floods in europe uh you know
fires indian us
uh you know cyclones across the world
three hundred and twenty one billion
dollars we had fifty instances of fifty
billion dollar plus uh you know instance
uh if you look at just the indian
context uh
traditionally in the past maybe five six
years back we would have one cyclone
every three four years last year we
three we have three cycles uh top tail
yas
right
if you look at the west coast of india
you would never get uh cyclones we've
had top team this year
we served last year so
it is clearly evident to all of us who
are willing to
accept
data and see the reality
there is a huge change that is happening
i mean
the temperatures are going up we all
talk about it the
temperature of the you know the ocean
temperatures going up that's a that's a
huge risk and uh the type of incident
that we are getting are much more
extreme
now in terms of preparedness uh i think
people are beginning to realize that
this is an this is an issue but i don't
see too much of a
a priory
you know kind of fanatically you know
all of that into
the risk management practices we are
seeing some progressive organizations
who are thinking about designing uh
for
climate change i mean you know looking
at identification of climate change look
at what they can do to improve their uh
their infrastructure to take care of
events of these nature and on a constant
basis monitor in events that have
happened what we are seeing is people
are people are a lot more prepared so
people are observing and monitoring
what's happening and taking uh
precautions so we had a client who
uh because of top day they were
wondering about their
road going up to the jetty and they
actually which was in the in the line of
the other of those on the cyclone they
actually built a separate uh you know
access road before the cyclone hit and
that helped them save their operations
into the business continuity et cetera
so people are taking some of those uh
you know proactive steps but at scale
the answer is no
but we really need to uh realize that
this is a huge impact that's going to
hit us and it's hitting us as we speak
but will hit us even more going
okay now one more word on risk
management uh you know
need it be seen only as a cost uh is it
increasingly also being seen as a value
creation tool you heard me speak about
this for many years as you've done the
risk
so we've always believed that risk
management is a strategic tool strategic
differentiator uh
well-run and successful organizations uh
people who have succeeded over years
have constantly taken advantage of risk
management as a strategic differentiator
yes that's what gives them going in a
sustained manner over the years
if you don't you know handle this well
you can't take the
risk that you need to take as a business
to scale up and grow
and what what we're seeing is
increasingly there is a lot more
awareness and consciousness so from
society at large you know people are
challenging corporates in terms of their
reputation
you know risk in terms of their
sustainability initiatives in terms of
investors looking at eac scores so my
sense is that there are many forces
coming together to uh
ask corporates to you know even if they
haven't been focusing on some of these
things
asking them to take
action on risk management and i think
the last two years as we discussed
earlier clearly people have seen the
benefit of
managing risk better companies which
were prepared to some extent you know
you can't prepare for it but we prayed
in terms of mindset of having
resilience and agility i think they have
done done better and that's something
that people have taken away from these
two years so
my view is that you know as we go ahead
and particularly given what we have what
the world is going through in terms of
potential and orderly
i think we are
getting into a you know phase where
people do value risk management
okay oh absolutely and i value what i
learned from i say salomon and this
conversation a lot more you know you
would have thought that
to be in an insurance company you should
either have done actuarial sciences or
maybe have degrees in finance but it now
looks like
insurers like you have to be amateur
epidemiologists amateur climatologists
amateurs cyberist managers i mean you
have to be multifaceted uh that's what
reality is demanding from you and you
are coming up to speed thank you very
much mr dhaka for joining me in this
extremely enlightening chat
[Music]
ici fair lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards honoring
the new age risk management
practitioners
[Music]
innovate
enable